Guide to the Time Inc. Oral History Project Records 1984-1994 MS 3009-RG 33
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Oral History Project Records
1984-1994
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 33
3 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
The Oral History Project Records include background preparation research, transcripts, and audiovisual material from interviews of Time Inc. staff conducted by the Time Inc. Archives between 1984 and 1994.
Arrangement Note
Organized alphabetically by last name based on the original order.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers with some restrictions. Materials created within the past 35 years also may be subject to restriction on a case-by-case basis. Unreformatted audiovisual material in the collection is not accessible. Box 1812 is only audiovisual material.
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents Note
According to the records and oral history releases, interviews were conducted by the Time Inc. Archives between 1984 and 1994. Papers consist of background preparation research to formulate interview questions including copies of archival material and news clippings; notes of possible questions to ask; correspondence with the interview subject setting up interview and discussing their review of transcripts; and transcripts. Some paper files include audiovisual of the interviews. A large portion of audiovisual was housed separately from the papers. Not all individuals have transcripts or audiovisual material, and it is noted when these materials exist.
Individuals selected for interview are mainly editors, reporters, or photographers including members of corporate editorial such as editor-in-chief Donovan Hedley, editorial director Ralph Graves, and assistant corporate editor Dave Maness; and Time editors Tom Griffith and Robert Sherrod; chief editor of March of Time Lothar Wolff; and Life photographers David Duncan, Alfred Eisenstaedt, and Albert Fenn.
Also included are heads of departments such as corporate vice president of law Gabe Perle, vice president of corporate public affairs Donald Wilson, and vice president and personnel director Robert Steed.
The project also includes those who held special positions or were involved in notable events in Time Inc.'s history such as: corporate historian Curt Prendergast; Henry R. Luce's sister Elisabeth Moore; Time cover researcher and coordinator Rosemary Frank; Eleanor Graves, an long-time employee who held several titles including programming director for Time-Life Films and assistant managing editor of the revived Life; and Carl and Shelley Mydans, the reporter and photographer team captured during World War II as prisoners-of-war while on assignment for Life.
Since some individuals were no longer living at the time this project commenced, it isn't certain if all files were created for interviews or were just background information collected during the project.
Accruals Note
Additional separated audiovisual material will be added if found during further processing of the Time Inc. Records.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Organization files; Corporation records; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Corporations -- History; Oral histories (document genres); Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Donovan, Hedley: Papers, 1989; 222154 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 1-2)
- Donovan, Hedley: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1989; 222856 (Offsite-box 1812)
  Scope and Contents Note
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Donovan, Hedley - Oral History 2/16/89."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Donovan, Hedley - Oral History 5/17/89 Tape I."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Donovan, Hedley - Oral History 5/17/89 Tape II."
- Duncan, David Douglas: Papers, undated; 222155 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 3)
- Eisenstaedt, Alfred: Papers, 1992; 222156 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 4)
- Eisenstaedt, Alfred: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1992; 222858 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Eisenstaedt, Alfred - Oral History Tape 1 A&B 3/20/92."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Eisenstaedt, Alfred - Oral History Tape 2 3/20/92."
- Fenn, Albert: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1991; 222859 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Fenn, Albert Oral History 4/21/91 Life Photographer tape IIA."
- Ford, Enfield "Flicky": Audio [RESTRICTED], 1994; 222863 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Ford, Enfield - Oral History 1/14/94."
- Frank, Rosemary: Papers, 1985; 222157 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 5-6)
- Frank, Rosemary: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1985; 222864 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Rosemary Frank 6/11/85 I."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Rosemary Frank II 6/11/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Rosemary Frank (dup) I 6/11/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Rosemary Frank (dup) II 6/11/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Rosemary Frank III (dup) 6/19/85."
- Graves, Eleanor: Papers and Audio [RESTRICTED], 1987; 222158 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 7-9)
  Includes transcripts and audiovisual material.
  1 audiotape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. Label on container: "Graves, Eleanor - Reminiscences 12/8/87 -see also - vcr collection - oral history."
- Graves, Ralph: Papers, 1987; 222160 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 10-11)
  Includes transcripts.
- Graves, Ralph: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1987; 223018 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 12-14)
  1 audiotape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Graves, Ralph - Oral History 4/28/87 Tape I see also - Video Tape."
  1 audiotape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Graves, Ralph - Oral History 5/5/87 Tape II see also - Video Tape."
  1 audiotape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Graves, Ralph - Oral History 5/5/87 Tape III see also - Video Tape."
- Griffith, Tom: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1993; 222873 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Griffith, Thomas - Oral History (2) (1951-1960 #2 2/17/93."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Griffith, Thomas - Oral History III 3/4/93 tape 1-A&B."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Griffith, Thomas - Oral History III 3/4/93 tape 2 A."
- Griffith, Tom: Videocassette [RESTRICTED], undated; 222162 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 15)
  1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On label: "Tom Griffith."
- Heiskell, Andrew: Audio [RESTRICTED], undated; 223019 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 16)
  1 audiotape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Heiskell (dup)."
- Hood, Alex: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1991; 222875 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "OH Alex Hood 3/29/91 A&B."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "OH Alex Hood 3/29/91 side C."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Hood, Alex 10/30/91 II2 A&B."
- Kessel, Dmitri: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1992; 222877 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Kessel, Dmitir - Oral history 9/30/92 Life photographer."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Kessel, Dmitir - Oral history 10/1/92 Life photographer II."
- Lloyd-Smith, Parker: Papers, undated; 222167 (Offsite-box 1810, Folder 17)
- Loengard, John: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1992; 222878 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Loengard, John - Oral history 3/4/92 Part I."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Loengard, John - Oral history 3/4/92 Part II."
- Low, Frances Levison: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1990; 222880 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Low, Frances Lovison - Life Oral History Tape I (A&B) 6/14/90."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Low, Frances Lovison - Life Oral History Tape II (A) 6/14/90."
- Maness, Dave: Papers, 1985-1986; 222168 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 1-4)
- Maness, Dave: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1985; 222881 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Maness, Dave Oral History 10/18/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Maness, Dave dup 10/18/85."
- Moore, Elisabeth Luce: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1991; 222882 (Offsite-box 1812)
  2 audiocassettes: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Moore, Elisabeth Luce - Oral history 4/17/91."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Moore, Elisabeth Luce - Oral history 6/12/91 A&B (1)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Moore, Elisabeth Luce - Oral history 6/12/91 A&B (2)."
- Munro, J. Richard: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1990-1992; 222883 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Munro, J. Richard Oral history Tape 1 & 2 11/12/90."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Munro, J. Richard Tape 3 (Oral History) 11/12/90."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Munro, J. Richard - Oral history II 2/10/92."
- Mydans, Carl: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1992-1993; 222884 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Mydans, Carl - Oral History (I) A&B 2/4/92."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Mydans, Carl - Oral History (II) A&B 2/4/92."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Mydans, Carl - Oral History 2/14/92 Tape II."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Carl Maydans III (1) 5/5/93."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Carl Maydans III (2) 5/5/93."
- Mydans, Shelley: Papers, 1986; 222175 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 5-6)
- Mydans, Shelley: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1986; 222892 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Mydans, Shelley - Oral history 8/1/86 Life (1 of 2)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Mydans, Shelley - Oral history 8/6/86 Life (2 of 2)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Mydans, Shelley 8/1/86."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Mydans, Shelley (dup) Tape II A&B 8/5/86."
- Perle, E. Gabriel: Papers and Audio [RESTRICTED], 1984; 222181 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 7-9)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Gabe Perle - 11/12/84 (E. Felsher)."
- Perle, E. Gabriel: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1984; 222895 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Perle, E. Gabriel - Oral history 11/15/84 (Tape 2. See folder for restricted tape 1.)"
- Prendergast, Curt: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Offsite-box 1812)
  Scope and Contents
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Prendergast, Curt-Oral Hist. 6/26/86. TLAS (with Cal Whipple."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Prendergast Curt (dup) - TLAS - 6/26/86. Oral History - Elaine Felsher with Cal Whipple."
- Prideaux, Tom: Papers, undated; 222186 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 10)
- Pitt, James: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1990; 222904 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Pitt, James E. - Oral history 5/17/90 #1 & #2 (Dir. of Publicity)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Pitt, James E. - Oral history 5/17/90 #3 (Dir. of Publicity)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Pitt, James E. 7/18/90 Oral history (Corp Pub/ Aff. '47-'70)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Pitt, James E. 7/18/90 Oral history Tape II (1) (Corp Pub/ Aff. '47-'70)."
- Rauch, Rudolph: Papers, 1987; 222187 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 11)
- Rauch, Rudolph: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1987?; 223020 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 12)
  1 audiotape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Rudolph Rauch."
- Rowan, Roy: Papers, 1987; 222188 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 13)
- Rowan, Roy: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1987?; 222906 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label side A: "Rowan, Roy - Reel 1 side 1 Tape 1."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label side A: "Rowan, Roy - Reel 1 side 3 #2."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label side A: " Tape __ Side I Roy Rowan #3."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label side A: " Tape __ Side __ Roy Rowan #4."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label side A: " Tape 5 Side __ Roy Rowan."
- Sherrod, Robert: Papers, 1985; 222189 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 14)
- Sherrod, Robert: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1985; 222911 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Sherrod, Robert - Oral Hist. 3/19/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "(Dup) Oral History Bob Sherrod 3/19/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Sherrod, Robert - Oral Hist. 3/27/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Sherrod 3/27 dup end of tape."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Robert Sherrod II (dup) 3/27/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Sherrod, Robert - Oral Hist. 3/28/85 4/6/85 (Side B partially restricted)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Bob Sherrod (dup) 3/28/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "______ side not to be transcribed per Sherrod 3/28/85 (dup) This side OK to transcribe."
- Steed, Robert: Papers, 1985; 222192 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 15)
- Steed, Robert: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1985; 222918 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Steed, Robert-Oral Hist. 2/21/85 Personnel Director."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Steed, Robert 2/21/85 Personnel."
- Steinbauer, Mary: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1994; 222919 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Steinbauer, Mary - Oral history 4/22/94 Time Life Books 8mm."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Steinbauer, Mary - Oral history 4/22/94 Time Life Book) I (A&B)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Steinbauer, Mary - Oral history 4/22/94 Time Life Books II."
- Stout, Elizabeth Davis: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1986; 223006 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container label: "Elizabeth Stout Davis Fortune Researcher '29-'31 5/19/86."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "(Davis) Elizabeth Stout Fortune - 1/29/11/31 Oral Hist. 5/19/86."
- Whipple, A. B. C.: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1986; 223007 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Whipple, A. B. C. - Oral hist. 6/26/86."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Whipple, A. B. C. 6/26/86 (dup) F 6/26/86."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "6/26/86 Whipple, A. B. C. (dup)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Whipple, A. B. C. - Oral hist. 7/9/86."
  2 audiocassettes: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "7/9/86 Whipple, A. B. C. (dup)."
- White, Frank: Papers, 1986; 222193 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 16)
- White, Frank: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1986; 223005 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "White, Frank - Oral history 10/14/86 (Dup from VCR) part I."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "White, Frank - Oral history 10/14/86 (Dup from VCR) part II."
- Wilson, Donald: Papers, 1989; 222195 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 17-20)
- Wilson, Donald: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1989; 223008 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Wilson Donm. - oral history 9/25/89 A & B I (1 & 2)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Wilson Don M - oral history 9/25/89 tape I (3)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Wilson Don M - oral history 10/13/89 Tape II (1 & 2)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Wilson Don M - oral history 10/13/89 Tape II (3)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Wilson Don M - oral history 10/18/89 Tape III (1&2)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Wilson Don M - oral history 10/18/89 Tape III (3)."
- Wolff, Lothar: Papers, 1985; 222196 (Offsite-box 1811, Folder 21)
- Wolff, Lothar: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1985; 223009 (Offsite-box 1812)
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Wolff, Lothar M.O.T. 6/3/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Lothar Wolff 6/3/85 (dup)."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container: "Wolff, Lothar II 7/10/85."
  1 audiocassette: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: "Lothar Wolff II 7/10/85 dup."